Guide to the Reginald R. Isaacs papers, 1917-1988, [bulk 1946-1988]
Isaacs, Reginald R. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reginald R. Isaacs papers, 1917-1988, [bulk 1946-1988]
8468
Isaacs, Reginald R.,
15.6 Cubic Feet.
Correspondence, professional records, and reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of Isaacs' professional records as a planner in Chicago, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, South America, and other locations, including correspondence, working papers, and reports. Collection also includes materials related to his teaching career at Harvard University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Reginald R. Isaacs was an architect, city and regional planner, educator, and author. He studied architecture at the University of Minnesota and Harvard University under Walter Gropius, and he studied sociology and planning at the University of Chicago. Isaacs was active in architecture and planning projects in Chicago, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, South America, and other locations. At Harvard, he served as Charles Dyer Norton Professor of Regional Planning beginning in 1951, chaired the Department of City and Regional Planning during 1953-1964, and participated in the development of the urban design program. He wrote a two-volume biography of Walter Gropius, which was published in German as Walter Gropius: Der Mensch und sein Werk in 1983 and 1984. The English edition, Walter Gropius: An Illustrated Biography of the Creator of the Bauhaus, was edited posthumously and published in 1991.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of Isaacs' professional records as a planner in Chicago, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, South America, and other locations, including correspondence, working papers, and reports. Collection also includes materials related to his teaching career at Harvard University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Isaacs, Reginald R., 1911-1986
Subjects:
City planning -- United States.; City planning -- Virgin Islands.; City planning -- Puerto Rico.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Materials related to internal affairs at the Harvard Graduate School of Design are closed until 2030, except by permission of the donor (Box 8, 15 and 16).
RELATED MATERIALS
Additional personal and professional papers, including materials related to Isaacs' research on Walter Gropius, are held by the Archives of American Art. Please see the Reginald R. Isaacs papers, circa 1842-1991 (bulk 1928-1991), Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Course material, 1946-1988
  - Metropolitan Areas Planning Materials - Old, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Metropolitan Areas Planning Materials - Old, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Regional Planning Lecture Discussion Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Metropolitan and Regional Areas Courses Description, 1976-08 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Including Blucher Notes
  - Chicago Metropolitan Area Planning Material, 1957-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Metropolitan Area Planning Lecture and Discussion Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Urban, Regional, Metropolitan Areas Design, 1958-09-09 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Definitions of Planning, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Bluchers?
  - Methods of Planning; Seminar Course, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Program (Process) for Planning, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reconnaissance Technique, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Contains Blucher's "Action for Cities"
  - Citizen Participation, 1966 Spring (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Process of Evaluation, 1967 Spring, Fall (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Housing Lectures, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Community Conservation, 1954-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Community Facilities Planning, 1957-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Including Syracuse Items
  - Theory/Role of Institutions in Planning, 1955-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Venezuela, Ecuador, Uruguay, Costa Rica, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Colombia, 1971; Hernandez, Mariano Ospina (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Student Papers in Other Languages, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Neighborhood Concept, 1946-1952 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Autograph annotation
  - Law and Constitution, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Excerpt From Vote, 1957-04-11 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Gropius At/In Harvard, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Architectural Record College Plans, 1947-12 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Housing & Community Facilities Final Exam, 1957-1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Mark Isaacs Correspondence, 1988-02 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Course Material, 1960-1967 (Box 12, Folder 34)
- Series II. Professional work, 1917-1988
  - Encyclopedia of Architecture Excerpts and Illustration Requests, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Program for the Planning of Memorial Rehabilitation Center Hospital, Santa Barbara, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Manuscript and Documentation for Encyclopedia of Architecture, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - First Annual Progress Report of the MRH Planning Staff, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Second Annual Progress Report of the MRH Planning Staff, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Third Annual Progress Report of the MRH Planning Staff, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fourth Annual Progress Report of the MRH Planning Staff, 1949-12-31 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fifth Annual Progress Report of the MRH Planning Staff, 1950-12-31 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Eight Annual Progress Report of the MRH Planning Staff, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ninth Annual Progress Report of the MRH Planning Staff, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Tenth Annual Progress Report of the MRH Planning Staff, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Eleventh Annual Progress Report of the MRH Planning Staff, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Twelfth Annual Progress Report of the MRH Planning Staff, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Draft of Conservation of Beaches, 1967-08 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Proyecto de ley sobre reforma integral urbana, 1970-12; Hernandez, Mariano Ospina (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Ensayos sobre planificacion, 1966-01 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - File Lecture on Citizen Participation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Marcel Breuer Documents and Research Paper, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Goals for Planning, Louis Wirth Documentation, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Louis Wirth Documentation, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Photographic Plates for Encyclopedia of Architecture, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Metas, directivas, programas, instrumentacion y evaluacion en planeamiento para Chile, 1964-10 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Planificacion regional para desarollo en Argentina, 1961-10 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Primer plan regional de desarollo para el Oriente Antioqueno, 1964-01; Hernandez, Mariano Ospina (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Revista de facultad de arquitecture Uruguay, 1962-02 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Feasibility of a Central Urban Area on the Island of St. Croix, 1969-02 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Proposed Zoning Laws for the US Virgin Islands, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - The Social and Economic Effect of High-Rise, High-Density Housing, 1967-09 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Gropius-Bauhaus Archive Documents, 1967-1986 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Puerto Rican Planning Article and Document, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Spanish Class Notes and Examinations, 1960 Summer (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Puerto Rico Planning Board, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Proposed Planning Program University of Puerto Rico, 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Metropolitan Area Planning - Ponce, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Instituto medico del norte Project Proposal, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - A Master Plan to Guide the Redevelopment of Clinica Dr. Pila, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Review of the Workable Program for Community Improvement in Puerto Rico, 1968-07 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Training for Town and Country Planning, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Walter Gropius, 1981-03 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Planner's Responsibility to Urban Society, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Feeling Bad and Feeling Badly 5th Draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    An Assertive and Tendentious Essay on the Mythology of Affectivity
  - City Planning: A Selection of Readings in its Theory and Practice, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Conservation 1 of 3, 1953-01-31 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Conservation 2 of 3, 1953-01-31 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Conservation 3 of 3, 1953-01-31 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Federal Home Loan Bank Review, 1944-10-1945-09 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Land Economies, 1949-02-1949-08 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Various Publications, 1945-1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Manual of Procedure of the Viring Islands Planning Board Draft, 1967-07 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Virgin Islands Consultancy Contracts, Bills, and Invoices, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Development of the US Virgin Islands Draft, 1967-12 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Overall Program Design for Comprehensive Planning, 1970-12-21 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Shipley's Battery Work US Virgin Islands, 1974-04 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Virgin Islands Varia, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Conservation of Beaches Drafts, 1967-08-1967-09 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Urban Renewal and Housing Administration, Puerto Rico
  - Planning for San Juan, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Plan of the Puerto Rico medical center, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Puerto Rico work, 1957-1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - International Center for Artists and Scientists, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Goals for planning in Puerto Rico, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Instituto de Cultura Puertorriquena
  - San Juan planning, 1958-1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Virgin Island consultation work, 1 of 2, 1963-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Virgin Island consultation work, 2 of 2, 1963-1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Denmark slides, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Unlabeled slides (Denmark?), 1964 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Denmark negatives and slides, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Unlabeled negatives, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Planning in Puerto Rico, 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Consultants activities, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - A proposed TV series in US and Virgin Islands, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Virgin Islands, 1963-1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Log of the Planning Office for Urban Affairs, 1969-1970; Gorden, Rev. Michael F. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Mount Auburn cemetery, Date unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Newton S. Friedman and Associates. P.A.
  - "Housing as a townbuilding problem", Undated; Gropius, Walter (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Unidentified photocopies, Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified photos, Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Galley proofs of "Walter Gropius, the early years", Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Virgin Islands, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Environmental issues, Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Photos of Harvard graduate center, Undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Metropolitan planning for the Saybrook-Lyme area, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Report on Boston Municipa; Employees, 9th Annual Conferama, 1964-11-19-1964-11-20 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Revista de Administracao Municipal, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Housing Publications, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1958 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1965-10 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Walter Gropius and the Bauhaus Book Material, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Mies Van der Rohe, 1950-1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Gropius Illustration Copies, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Gropius Manuscript Draft, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Gropius Book Sample Edits 1st Draft, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Gropius Book Sample Edits 2nd Draft, Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Gropius Book Sample Edits Final Version, Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Gropius Book Letters from Van der Leun, 1986-11 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Reginald Isaacs Obituary Materials, 1986-05-1986-10 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Isaacs: Gropius at Harvard Publication, 1983-05 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Regional Isaacs Biography Material, 1977-1986 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Frederic Law Olmstead Biography Materials, 1986-05 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Ludwig Mies Van der Rohe Biography Materials, 1970-07 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Le Corbusier Biography Materials, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Analysis and Evaluation of the General Hospital, 1959-11 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Policies for the Planning of the Medical Center of Mayaguez, 1960-03 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Program for the Planning of the Medical Center of Mayaguez, 1961-04 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Regional Planning Theory: A Reply to the British Challenge, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Report of the Minnesota State Planning Board Part 1, 1936-12 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Regional Planning Part II: Saint Louis Region, 1936-06 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - A Decade of Regional Planning in New England, 1943-06 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - A History of Prefabrication, 1945-09 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Woodlawn: A Study in Community Conservation, 1946-07 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 7th Congress of the International Union of Architects, 1963-09 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Evaluation and Updating of the 1967 Study Design, 1971-04 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Regional Survey of New York and its Environs Vol. 1, Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Preliminary Report on Reconnaissance in Latin America, 1959-12 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Goals and Values for South America: The beginning point of the Planning Process, 1969-05-16 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Latin America, 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Final Report: Housing and Urban Technological Research and Development, Undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Community Renewal Program Preliminary Report, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Community Renewal Program Regional and Metropolitan Aspects, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Original Presentation Material and American Society of Landscape Architects, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Social Studies for MRH and Outlines, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - An Opportunity for Private and Public Investment in Rebuilding Chicago, 1946-1952 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Michael Reese Hospital Development, 1947-1951 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Publications Chicago Development, 1947-1955 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - American Society of Planning Officials Newsletter and Walter H. Blucher Spech, 1943-1957 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Neighborhood Theory, 1948-1958 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Michael Reese Hospital Community Overlook, 1949-1956 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Thesis Drafts for the Neighborhood Theory, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Walter H. Blucher Letters, 1945-1961 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Walter H. Blucher Letters, 1961-1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Walter H. Blucher Letters and Memos, 1962-1981 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Original File Lecture on Citizen Participation, 1949-12-08 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Discussion for the Virgin Islands Planning Board, 1965-12-20 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - An Act to Provide Regional Planning for the Baltimore Regional Area, 1962-11-10 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - The Art, Education, and Responsibilities of Planners, Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Letter to Karl-Heinz, 1986-06-09 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Impington Slides, 1966-07 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Athens Slides, 1965-07 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Reese and Chicago Renewal Press and Related Material, 1952-1960 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Plant Material for the Virgin Islands, Undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence with Leigh B. Block, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Michael Reese Hospital Documents, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Carl Grip, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Misc. Articles, 1963-1971 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Bauhaus Archive Photos, Undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Clarence Tom Hawaii Documents, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence with Winfried Nerginger Bauhaus Archive, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Human Conditions; The Cultural Basis of Educational Development, 1984-06 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Internal affairs at the Harvard Graduate School of Design, 1963-1972 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Access restrictions apply.
  - Bibliography-Isaacs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Crimson and Harvard University Gazette, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Harvard Crimson and Harvard University Gazette, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Various Publications, 1946-1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Patrick Geddes: Some Neglected Concepts, Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Flyspeck Affair and WHB Correspondence, 1955-1960 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Syracuse Affair and WHB Correspondence, 1944-1957 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - American Institute of Planners WWII Newsletter, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Virgin Islands Planning Office Annual Report, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Metropolitan Area Planning for the South Central Met. Area, 1958-07-18 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Fenway-Parker Hill Area Its Problems and Potential, 1958-10 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Carleton Area Planning Project Report, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - American Council to Improve Our Neighborhoods (ACTION), Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Memorandum: Organization for Research (ACTION), 1954-11 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Architecture and Design in the Age of Science, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Planning Publications, 1951-1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Architecture Association Quarterly, 1969-10 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Harvard Crimson and New Yorker Articles, 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Harvard GSD Poster for Alumni Contribution, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Vermont Interim Land Capability Plan, 1971-06 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Photographic Plates for Encyclopedia of Architecture, Undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - The Education of Planners - An Epilogue, 1962-01-31 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Architectural Forum, 1958-02 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Consideraciones sobre la cultura de Puerto Rico en la planificacion, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - University of Virginia, Student Research Project US Virgin Islands, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Planning in Hartford W.H. Blucher, 1965-10 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Zoning in the Virgin Islands WHB, 1969-03 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - University of British Columbia, Canadian Immigration, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Mies Van der Rohe, Gropius, and the Bauhaus, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Revisions on Chapter 3 Walter Blucher and Housing, 1985-01-24 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Richard F. Babcock Correspondence, 1986-08-15 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - A Legal View of the Flood Plains, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Harvard Commencement Ceremonies, 1968-06-13 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - An Introduction to the Science of the Natural Environment, 1954-06 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Course with Belaunde-Terry, 1959-1968 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Assessment of UN Argentina City and Regional Planning Program Proposal, 1963-08-26 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - UN Applications Correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Argentina Project Proposal Conclusions and Recommendations, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Argentina Application to Special Fund, 1963-05 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - United Nations, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Argentina City and Regional Planning Program, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Argentina City and Regional Planning Program, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Aspects of Rehabilitation Argentina, 1950-1978 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Argentina Notes, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Argentina United Nations Project, 1961-12 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Brazil Notes, 1959-1968 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Planning in Chile Draft, 1964-06 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Planning in Chile Draft, 1964-06-1964-10 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Chile Consultant Material, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Colombia, 1962-07 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Colombia Planning, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Cuba, 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Cuba Related Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Dominican Republic Correspondence, 1962-08-02 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Honduras, 1959-1978 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Mexico, 1961-1969 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Nicaragua, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Panama, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Peru, 1959-1962 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - San Salvador, El Salvador, 1959-06 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Venezuela, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Master Plan of Dacca City, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Indiana Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Power, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Contracts, 1967-1977 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Gulf Regional Planning Committee, 1972-1976 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Indiana, 1969-1979 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Fort Wayne, Indiana, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Report Gulf Regional Planning Commission, 1973-09-30 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Gulf Regional Planning Commission Profile, 1973-1978 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1973-1976 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Gulf Regional Planning Commission, 1973-03-01 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - City of Syracuse Planning, Housing and Urban Renewal, 1957-05 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - City of Syracuse - An Administrative Study, 1957-05 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Problems of United States Economic Development Volume 1, 1958-01 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Problems of United States Economic Development Volume 2, 1958-05 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Conservation and Renewal of Three Towns in the US Virgin Islands, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Industrialized Housing for Puerto Rico, 1971-04 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Lake Meadows, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - House and Home, 1953-10 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Metropolitan Planning in the United States, 1962-08 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Mount Sinai Hospital Planning Study, 1958-09 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Preliminary Report on a Research Program for ACTION, 1954-09-16 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Misc. Publications, 1917-1955 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Views on Public Housing, 1960-03 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Community Appraisal Study, 1951-1952 Spring, Fall (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Framingham: Your Town Your Problem, 1948-02 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Urban Sprawl and Health, 1959-01 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Gulf Regional Planning Commission Profile, 1971` (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Preliminary Draft Proceedings of 5th Urban Design Conference Harvard, 1961-04-14 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Photograph of Reginald Isaacs, Undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Committee to Prepare a Minute on the Life and Work of Walter Gropius, 1967-10-08 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Gropius Drafts and Related Correspondence, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Harvard-Radcliffe Hillel, 1981-12 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - A Civic Centre for Tallahassee Florida, 1956-08-01 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Architectural Consultant's Preface Michael Reese Hospital, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Misc. Planning Publications, 1935-1958 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Hispanic American Historical Review, 1975-08 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Harvard Graduate School of Design Alumni Book, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - A-F Correspondence, Date unknown (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - G-L Correspondence, Date unknown (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - M-Q Correspondence, Date unknown (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - R-Z Correspondence, Date unknown (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Regional Isaacs Radcliffe Crew Scull, 1975-1979 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Cuba Correspondence, 1961-05-17 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1968-08-22 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Chicago Community Appraisal Study, 1950-1962 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Printed Material, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Printed Material, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Harvard Publications, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Record of Names, Undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Barrier-Free Design, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Cards and Invitations, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Scull Dedication Photos, Date unknown (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Assorted Materials, 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Revista de la facultad de arquitecture Montevideo, 1961-09 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Children and the City, 1952-07 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - An Opportunity for Private and Public Investment in Rebuilding Chicago, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Democratic Planning in Action, 1946-01 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Daedalus, 1965 Spring (Box 12, Folder 27)